

Iran +989357320159 ali-heidari@outlook.com

Self-taught, innovated, motivated and experienced full stack developer who founded several startups and improved great team work ability. Completed and implemented many projects and services on major platforms.

Mentored, coached and guided interns and developers achieved a better team that defines the quality of the product.

Believes that healthy daily routing and habitats effect positively on the brain which is the most important tool of developers.

Work Experience

Full stack developer

05/2017 to Present

Dakkehchi.ir

Iran, Tehran

Dakkehchi is an online service for connecting 1 small (to middle size) shop with all nearby customers.

- Developed 2 Android apps for customers and shops which increased android users by 100%.
- Arranged data transfer between client and server by SignalR reduced the number of connections to only 5.
- Designed 3 services of the server by C#, .Net framework and SQL Server
- Implemented the MicroService approach by 5 independent services which decreased dependency bugs and achieved test-driven development.

Full stack developer

1/2020 to Present

IranSound.app

Iran, mashhad

IranSound is an Android app that listens to songs and tells you about it.

- Server engines made by Java to analyze and search more than 6000 musics.
- Android app records 10 seconds of music.
- ElasticSearch used for storing data reduced 30% ram usage.

Full stack developer

9/2018 to 10/2019

Manaandisheh.com

Iran, Mashhad

Manaandisheh is a growing company that is a subsidiary of Green-Web holding. Had different roles there:

- As a Full-stack developer working with 3 techs; Angular, .Net Core, and SQL Server.
- led a team as project manager was an exciting job which made me 1-leader and 2- better in team works.
- JavaScript, PHP and .Net Core used to create a logo maker project able to build more than 1 millions logs. Image processing using Skia Sharp was challenging truly.

Android developer

05/2017 to 05/2018

TCCO.ir

Iran, Mashhad

TCCO is an old company to create electrical devices.

- Created a remote controller for their burglar alarm device for android phones solved 1 big problem of users by the ability to control from distance.
- Completed a monitoring app for their AVL devices on android devices increased ease of use by 70%.

Developer

02/2014 to 05/2017

TSIP

Iran, Mashhad

TSIP was a software company known by its ERP system.

- Helped them to redesign their software as a web app had 2 benefits, more users and removed platform dependant.
- Developed a system for monitoring AVL and handheld devices. Android app alongside side of the web app added 90% users.

Skills C# - 6 years

Java - 5 years

JavaScript - 4 years

NodeJS - 1 year

SQL Server - 6 years

Angular - 1 year

ElasticSearch - 1 year

.Net Core - 2 years

Education

Azad university

Bachelor's Civil Engineering Iran, Bojnourd 05/2013 to 09/2017

Additional Information

Contributing to open source projects actively.

- SCM is a cent-os "run once" to config a raw server. Eased and speeded up to make the server ready.
- PipesHubs is a connector between services and applications as a middle hub to transfer data. Secured and facilitated communication between softwares.
- ABCCalculator is "Assignment Branch Condition" calculator for java sources. Helped to write cleaner code.

Articles

 NodeJS with JWT which is a guidance to develope a MVC app with JWT as an authenticator

Links

https://www.aheidari.com

https://github.com/ali-heidari

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-heidari-elpixeler/